

Fiacre Nsanzabandi

DATE OF BIRTH: 11/07/1988

CONTACT

Nationality: Burundian

Gender: Male

113, Rue de l'Alzette, 4011 Esch-sur-Alzette, Luxembourg



(+352) 691988265

https://fiacrensanzabandi.com

ABOUT MF

I am a software engineer experienced in Java EE programming. After 7 years of professional life in application development, I find it easy to integrate new projects and quickly acquire new knowledge on new subjects. I consider myself a dynamic, versatile and autodidact person and that allows me to be a very good team player. I like sharing the developer experience and it motivates me to move towards the professions of "tech leader", "team leader" or "scrum master".

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/05/2019 - CURRENT - Leudelange, Luxembourg

Developer for different customers and internal projectsSopra Steria

Clients

- SIB (Steria interconection box)
- Sopra Steria academy
- UCM (Union des classes moyennes)
- Sopra Steria digilab
- BCP Luxembourg

Tasks

- Conception & development of Java EE applications
- Java trainer for the Sopra Steria academy
- Participation in different POCs (Proof of concepts) aimed at improving the existing

Technical environment:

- WEB programming: Java EE, Spring batch, Spring boot, Angular, HTML5, CSS3
- Mobile programming: Android
- IT Ops & cloud: Docker, kubernetes, Google cloud platform, Ansible
- Collaboration & integration: Git, Jira, Jenkins 2, Maven, SVN
- Database: Oracle, Mysql

Methodology: Agile, scrum

01/01/2018 - 30/04/2019 - La Madeleine, France

Developer for the customer " Oney Bank "

Sopra Steria

Tasks

- Conception & development of Java EE applications for the customer
- Technical leader in clean coding

Technical environment

- WEB programming: Java EE, Spring boot, Spring batch, HTML5, CSS3. Angular IS
- Collaboration and integration: Git, Jira, Jenkins 2, Maven
- · Database: Oracle, Mysql

Methodology: Agile

Customer's domain: Banking

01/02/2016 - 31/12/2017 - La Madeleine, France

Developer for the customer « GIE AGORA » (IT center of the mutual health insurance for farmers in France)

Sopra Steria

Tasks

- Conception & development of Java EE applications for the customer
- Provide corrective maintenance
- Evolutions' costing
- WEB technical leader for new developers
- Analyst and team leader

Technical environment

- WEB Programming: Java EE, Struts, Spring batch, HTML5, CSS3, C etc.
- Database management tools: COBOL, DB2, CICS
- Collaboration and integration: Jira, CVS
- Applications' performances: JMeter & JProfiler.

Methodology: Agile

Customer's domain: Insurance

03/03/2014 - 31/01/2016 - La Madeleine, France

Developer for the client « AG2R LA MONDIALE »

Sopra Steria

Tasks

- Conception & development of Java EE applications for the customer
- Provide corrective maintenance
- Evolutions' costing
- WEB technical leader for new developers

Technical environment

- WEBprogramming: Java EE, GWT, JSF, Spring, HTML5, CSS3
- Database management tools: COBOL, DB2, CICS
- Collaboration & integration: Jira, ARS, ITSM, HPQC, clearcase, CVS

Functional environment: Insurance

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/09/2011 - 01/08/2014 - Rouen, France

Master's degree in software engineering

Université de Rouen

Professional studies on:

- software development methodologies
- various programming languages (WEB programming, Java, Java EE, C++, C#, etc.)

01/09/2008 - 01/07/2011 - Oran, Algeria

Bachelor's degree in mathematics & computer science

Université d'Oran

Programming:

- ∘ Java, C++, Qt
- Functional programming: prolog, CAML.

Mathematics: analyzes and algebra

Student scholarship of the Burundian government and UNESCO.

01/09/2007 - 01/06/2008

Gap year

Student at the University of Tanganyika Lake; Traveling across East Africa.

•

Secondary studies achievement in mathematics and physics Lycée du Lac Tanganyika

LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): French / Kirundi / Swahili

OTHER LANGUAGE(S):

English

Listening C2	Reading C2	Spoken production C2	Spoken interaction C2	Writing C1

German

Listening B1	Reading B1	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	Writing B1
		B2	B2	

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: AM
Driving Licence: B1
Driving Licence: B

JOB-RELATED SKILLS

Job-related skills

- **Programming languages**: Java, Kotlin, typescript, C++, C, C#, SQL, etc.
- **WEB programming**: Java EE (JSP/Servlet, etc.), Spring (Spring boot, Spring MVC, etc.), Angular, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, etc.
- IT Ops & cloud: Docker, kubernetes, Ansible, Google cloud platform
- JavaEE tools & frameworks: Playframework, GWT, Zkoss, JUnit, Aspectl, SoapUl, postman etc.
- Profiling and performances: JMeter & JProfiler
- Mobile development: Android
- **Collaboration & integration**: Git, CVS, Maven, Nexus, Sonar, lenkins, lira
- **Project management**: Agile methods (Scrum, XP)
- Development tools (IDE): Eclipse, Intellij
- Database tools: MySQL, Postgresql, Oracle, non-relational databases notions (eXist)
- Servers: Tomcat, TomEE, glassfish, JBoss, Weblogic
- os: Linux & Windows

I am a full stack developer: 60% of my time doing java EE and 40% working on other technologies.